Brice Folléas

SOFTWARE ENGINEER





(+81) 70-9289-0238 brice.folleas@gmail.com thttps://b-folleas.github.io/portfolio/

PROFILE

Persistent and efficient full stack engineer with 4+ years of experience in application layers, presentation layers and databases. Used to working in a multinational context with collaborators in various countries. Currently based in Kawasaki, Kanagawa, I am looking for a new job opportunity in the Tokyo area.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Engineer, Fiducial

2019-09 - Present

Project management and developement of large-scale business applications for the internal accounting

- · Software architecture design for different intercommunicating modules
- · Design and integration of user interfaces, maintenance of interface consistency on existing projects
- Database model design, query implementation, performance analysis and data flow management
- Leading project meetings and exchange with business users
- Supervision of the work of an apprentice and an international employee in English

Working on the following modules: budget management, customer management, contractual documents and time management.

PHP Symfony / Vue.js / Java Springboot / PostgreSQL / Vagrant / Git / Pentaho Data Integration (ETL)

Full Stack Developer, Conity

2019-04 - 2019-06

Development of new features for the customer relationship platform:

- · Integration of user interfaces on existing applications
- Automated tests realisation
- Implementation of automated tests in a continuous integration pipeline

PHP Symfony / Twig / Behat / Docker / Git / GitLab CI/CD

SKILLS

Programming	Databases	Environnement
JavaScript / Vue.js	SQL (PostgreSQL / Oracle)	OS (Linux / Windows)
PHP / Symfony	Pentaho Data Integration (ETL)	Git
Python / Django	NoSQL (MongoDB)	Docker / Vagrant
Java / Springboot	Management	Powershell
HTML/CSS	Scrum & Agile Methodologies	

EDUCATION

Engineer's degree in computer Science and communication Networks

2019 - 2022 : CPE Lyon, Lyon, France

Specialization in Information System

End-of-course group project: Movie recommendation web application based on a micro-services architecture and a clusterization module for recommendation with Agile methodologies management. Acting as the **Scrum Master** of the group.

Project Stack: Java (Springboot) / Node.js / Angular / Python (Pandas / Scikit Learn) / PostgreSQL /

MongoDB / Docker

Relevant coursework: Software Architecture, Advanced Software Programming, Project Management, Relational Database Design & SQL, UI & UX Design, Search Engine Optimization

Associate's degree preparation

2019: Dawson College, Westmount, Canada

Exchange program in Computer Science within an English speaking College

Relevant coursework: Advanced Software Programming (Java), Project Management

Associate's degree in Computer Science

2017 - 2019: IUT Lyon 1, Lyon, France

Relevant coursework: Software Programming, Relational Database Design & SQL, UI & UX Design

LANGUAGES

English Full professional capacity

Cambridge English Proficiency (C2) - 2022

Japanese Limited professional capacity

Currently preparing for the JLPT N3 exam / Following classes from Atsugi Japanese Volunteer Association (C1)

French Mother tongue

HOBBIES

Crossfit - Cross-country running (2022 Marathon of Lyon) - Swimming Geography - Animation - Piano - Chess